Holli Would if she could ...and she will
Cool World is a animation, comedy, fantasy film directed by Ralph Bakshi.
While incarcerated for murder, cartoonist Jack Deebs found escape by creating Cool
World, a series featuring a voluptuous femme fatale named Holli Would.
But the artist becomes a prisoner of his own fantasies when Holli transports Jack
into Cool World with a scheme to seduce him and bring herself to life.
Hard-boiled detective Frank Harris – the only other human in Cool World – cautions Jack
with the law: Noids (humans) don't have sex with doodles (cartoons).
However, flesh proves weaker than ink as Holli takes human form in Las Vegas, staring in
a trans-universal chase that threatens the destruction of both worlds.
Holli Would, played by Kim Basinger.
Jack Deebs, played by Gabriel Byrne.
Detective Frank Harris, played by Brad Pitt.
Jennifer Malley, played by Michele Abrams.
Isabelle Malley, played by Deirdre O'Connell.
Agatha Rose Harris, played by Janni Brenn.
Cool World is a 1992 American live-action animated fantasy film directed by
Ralph Bakshi and written by Michael Grais and Mark Victor.
The film stars Kim Basinger, Gabriel Byrne and Brad Pitt.
Its plot follows a cartoonist who finds himself in a cartoon-like universe he believes he created,
where he is seduced by one of the characters, a femme fatale who wants to become human.
Following the success of Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988) and his own professional resurgence in
television in the late 1980s, Bakshi conceived Cool World as a horror film.
He brought the idea to Paramount Pictures, and became attached to direct; it was his
first feature film in nearly a decade, and intended as his comeback.
However, interference from producer Frank Mancuso Jr.
led to an extensive rewrite from Michael Grais, Mark
Victor, and an uncredited Larry Gross.
As a result, relations between Bakshi, Mancuso, and the studio
deteriorated, and the film had a highly tumultuous production.
Cool World was released in the United States by
Paramount Pictures on July 10, 1992.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, and was a box-office
failure, grossing $14 million against a production budget of $28 million.
The film explores themes of cartoon, seduction, comic
book, alternate dimension, adult animation.
The tone is lighthearted.